So, you have your stock prices adjusted for corporate actions like splits and dividends.
你已经根据分割和股息等企业行为调整股价
How do you use this information to perform trading?
如何使用这些信息进行交易呢？
When you buy, when you sell,
何时买入？何时卖出？
or even which stocks do you buy or sell.
甚至买卖哪些股票？
You can take these decisions based on signals
你可以从历史股价数据中推理出一些信号
that can be derived from historical price data.
并根据这些信号做出决策
The first step in this process is to compute
第一步是计算
statistical measures that are called indicators.
统计学度量 称为指标
You can think of the raw price of a stock as the most basic kind of indicator.
你可以将原始股价看做最基本的指标
Here are the stock prices for Facebook over a one-year period.
图中是 Facebook 一年的股价走势图
The latest price is about $115.
最新价格约为 115 美元
Is that good? Should we buy some Facebook shares?
表现好吗？应该买一些 Facebook 股票吗？
Well, it's not clear.
不太清楚
The price seems to be jumping around a lot and
股价似乎一直跳动
we don't have a sense of where we should expect to be.
无法判断未来股价会怎样
If we had that,
如果我们知道未来预期股价
then we could check if their current price is significantly higher
就能查看当前股价是否比预期股价
or lower than the expected price and make a decision based on that.
高很多或低很多 并据此作出决策
So, what is the expected price of a stock?
股票的预期价格是多少？
Is it the average price from when it began trading?
是从开始交易起的平均价格吗？
That seems a little too extreme.
这种结论好像太极端了
Stocks can grow in orders of magnitude over the years.
股价可能会以数量级增长
Most current prices will be well over the average.
大多数的当前股价会比平均价格高很多
What might be relevant is the recent average price of the stock.
股票最近的平均价格可能更有用
Maybe over the past week or month,
例如上一周或上个月的平均价格
we can extend this idea throughout the history of
我们可以将这种想法延伸到整个股票历史记录中
the stock and compute the average of a fixed length window of time.
并计算固定期限内的平均价格
It's like moving the window one unit at
就好像将期限窗口一次移动一个时间单位
a time and taking the average price within that window.
并计算该窗口内的平均价格
This is known as the simple moving average or rolling mean.
称之为简单移动平均线或滚动平均线
We could devise a trading strategy that looks for
我们可以根据交易策略寻找
large deviations from the moving average,
离移动平均线很远的偏离项
and generate trading signals based on that.
并据此生成交易信号
For instance, if a stock falls too far below its average,
例如 如果某只股票比平均线低很多
then we should buy it,
那么应该买入
or if it rises too far above,
如果升高很多
then we should sell.
那么应该卖出
But, how much is too much.
但是到底高低幅度是多少
Using a constant number or a threshold does not seem like a good idea.
使用常数或阈值似乎不合适
Different stocks trade at different price levels.
不同的股票以不同的价格水平交易
We need a measure that is tied to the price of the stock,
我们需要一个与股价相关的指标
maybe some fraction of the stock price.
例如股票的一小部分
But again, what fraction? We don't know.
一小部分是多少呢？我们不知道
Some stocks jump around a lot.
有些股票波动很大
Some are more stable.
有些更稳定
A better idea might be to compute
更好的指标是
the threshold from the jumpiness or volatility of the stock.
计算股票跳跃性或波动性的阈值
How about standard deviation?
例如标准差？
In fact, we can reuse the windowing idea and compute
实际上 我们可以再次使用窗口概念
standard deviation over the same fixed length window across time.
并计算固定长度的时间窗口上的标准差
These lines are called Bollinger bands.
这些线称为布林带
All these peaks sticking above the upper band
所有这些超出上轨线的峰值
are signaling that the stock is trading at a higher price than normal.
表示股票的交易价超出了正常值
The dips below the lower band are signaling abnormally low price.
低于下轨线的峰值表示非常低的价格
One problem that you might notice is that there's too many such points.
有一个问题是 这样的点太多了
We can reduce them by increasing the width of the bands.
我们可以通过增加布林带的宽度解决这一问题
That is, by considering a wider range of variation to be normal.
即认为正常的变化范围更大
A common threshold is to choose two standard deviations above and below.
常见阈值是以移动平均线为准加和减两个标准差的值
Now, we have far fewer outliers.
现在的离群值少多了
But the question remains what do we do with these outlying points?
问题是 如何处理这些离群值？
Sometimes we get short burst of outliers.
有时候出现短的离群值脉冲
So, should we buy or sell each of these points?
我们在每个这样的点都买卖吗？
If you think about it,
思考下后会发现
when the price falls below the lower band,
如果价格低于下轨线
you don't really know if it's going to keep falling or is it going to rise back up.
我们不知道是继续下跌还是会上升
Maybe it's wiser to focus on these inflection points.
或许应该关注这些拐点
When the price is below the lower band and starts to cross back inside towards the mean,
当价格低于下轨线并开始交叉 离均值更近时
that should be a good time to buy.
这时候应该买入
The price is still fairly low and on a rise.
价格依然很低并且要上升
On the other side,
另一方面
we can sell when the price crosses down the upper band to the inside.
当价格与上轨线交叉并跑到里面时 我们可以卖出
This gives us a series of buy and sell signals.
这些就是买卖信号
At this point, you must be wondering,
这时候 你肯定会疑问
how much money would I make from following these signals.
如果按照这些信号交易 我能赚多少？
Well, that opens up a whole can of worms.
这就要考虑很多因素了
We'll have to decide how much money you invest to account for
需要确定你将投资多少金额
the brokerage charges and for a few other things.
并考虑到佣金和其他费用
Let's just kick this can down the road and
先别管这些
we will look at again when we talk about backtesting.
之后讨论回溯测试时会讲解
For now, think about the indicators we just computed.
暂时先记住我们刚计算的指标
Simple moving average and
包括简单移动平均线和标准差
standard deviation and the trading signals we derived from them.
以及根据它们推出的交易信号
This was a fairly simple approach.
这些指标比较简单
See if you can compute other indicators and
你能根据价格和成交量数据
better signals from the price and volume data.
算出其他指标和更好的信号吗？